♬ 引き合うように 重なる波紋
Mr. Joestar has won the battle!
♬～
But in the process... he lost everything he had!
♬ 誇りの道を往く者に
太陽の導きを
He's been in the hospital for three days...
But now he's all alone in the world!
There's not much I can do... but at least I can show him that there's still so much to live for!
♬ 野望の果てを目指す者に
生け贄を
♬～
♬ 震えるほど心
燃え尽きるほど熱く
Sora koboreochita futatsu no hoshi ga
Two stars fall from the sky
♬ その手から放て 鼓動
Original Translation:
Mudasubs
Hikari to yami no minamo suikomareteyuku
One shining in the light, the other sinking into darkness
♬ 身体 漲る勇気で
♬ 迷いなき覚悟に喝采を
Hikiau you ni kasanaru hamon
A ripple drawing the two of them together
♬ その血の運命 ジョジョ
Quality Check:
Tonitonichopchop
Hokori no michi wo yuku mono ni taiyou no michibiki wo
One will walk the path of pride and receive the sun's guidance
♬～
Yabou no hate wo mezasu mono ni
One will walk the path of unbridled ambition...
Ikenie wo
Demanding sacrifice!
Furueru hodo kokoro moetsukiru hodo atsuku
Let that burning in your soul calm the trembling of your heart
Timing/Typesetting/Encoding:
Fadeout4
Sono te kara hanate kodou
Strike down your fears,
Karada minagiru yuuki de
With courage coursing through your veins!
Mayou naki kakugo ni kassai wo
You cannot overcome your pain unless you can accept...
Raw Hunter:
WRRRRY
Sono chi no sadame
The legacy of your bloodline!
Jojo!
http://www.some-stuffs.com/
Episode 4: "Overdrive"
(ｽﾋﾟｰﾄﾞﾜｺﾞﾝ)《心だ！➡
Heart!
What he needs right now... is heart!
あの人には 今
心が 必要なんだ！》
ん？
It's the middle of the night...
(ｽﾋﾟｰﾄﾞﾜｺﾞﾝ)《真夜中だというのに➡
Why is there light coming from Mr. Joestar's room?
ジョースターさんの病室から
明かりが？》
W-Who is that?!
(ｽﾋﾟｰﾄﾞﾜｺﾞﾝ)《こ… これは!?》
Th-that woman...
(ｽﾋﾟｰﾄﾞﾜｺﾞﾝ)《あ… あの女は！➡
If she's a nurse, why would she be here at such a late hour?!
こんな遅くまで
付きっきりの看護を！》
(ｽﾋﾟｰﾄﾞﾜｺﾞﾝ)《あの手！
ふやけて 血が にじんでいる｡➡
Her hands... they're chapped, and stained with blood!
何百回 何千回と 冷水で
やけどを 冷やしているんだ！》
She must have cleaned and dressed his wounds hundreds, no... thousands of times!
(ｼﾞｮﾅｻﾝ)う… うぅ…｡
Thank goodness...
(ｴﾘﾅ)よかった…｡
He's conscious!
(ｽﾋﾟｰﾄﾞﾜｺﾞﾝ)《おお！ 意識を！》
The worst of it is over... you should be better, soon.
峠は越しました｡ もう大丈夫｡
You were... taking care of me?
君が ずっと看病を？
Could it... could it really be you?!
君は！ 君がここにいるなんて…｡
面影がある…｡
You look just like her...
いや まさか…
そんなはずはない｡
But... it can't be...
There's no way... although you look just like her...
すごく 似ているけど…｡
(ｴﾘﾅ)似てるって 誰に？
エリナ･ペンドルトンに？
Who do I look like, exactly?
Erina Pendleton, maybe?
ああっ！
It's been quite a while, Jonathan Joestar... Jojo.
お久しぶりです｡ ｼﾞｮﾅｻﾝ･ｼﾞｮｰｽﾀｰ…｡
ジョジョ｡
Erina! You've grown so much!
エリナ！ 大きくなったね｡
Well... certainly not as much as you have!
まあ!?
それは あなたの方ですわ！
(ｴﾘﾅ)でも…｡
But...
本当に しばらくです…｡
It really has been... such a long time...
ああ…｡
It has...
(ｽﾋﾟｰﾄﾞﾜｺﾞﾝ)《どうやら 俺じゃあ
役者不足だったようだぜ！➡
Looks like I wasn't as equipped for this task as I'd thought...
出直すとすっか！➡
I'll come back later.
スピードワゴンは
クールに去るぜ》
Time for Speedwagon to make like
a cool breeze and blow on through!
(ｴﾘﾅ)あっ…｡
はっ!?
つ… つい 気が緩んで 意識を…｡
I-I'm sorry, I suddenly felt faint...
まあ！ なんてこと!?
骨折している腕で 私を！
Oh my! I didn't mean to...
And you caught me, even with a broken arm?!
いつだって 支えるさ｡
I'll always be there to catch you when you fall.
人の出会いってのは➡
Maybe it's just fate that we meet the people in our lives...
運命で
決められてるのかもしれねえな｡
- Whitechapel Street, London -
(ｼﾞｬｯｸ)こんな 夜遅くまで遊んでる
堕落した女が！
What kind of filthy whore runs around town at this time of night?!
(女性)きゃあああ～！
(ﾃﾞｨｵ)大抵の人間は
心に 善のタガがある｡➡
I believe that most people have some
semblance of good within their hearts...
素晴らしい悪への
恐れがあるのだ｡
Something that instills terror in the presence of true evil...
But there are some... without even a whisper of good within them...
だが！ 極まれに
善なる タガのない人間がいる｡
The evil elite.
悪のエリート！
気に入ったぞ 闇のジャック！
And you are among that few, Jack of the Shadows...
このディオに 服従するのだ！
And now you shall bow before me!
素晴らしい力を与えてやる｡
今以上の快楽を 手にできるぞ｡
I can grant you magnificent power...
And with it, ecstasy beyond your wildest dreams!
(ﾜﾝﾁｪﾝ)ウリィ…｡
悩みは もう 何もない…｡
Wryyyyy...
Let your worries melt away...
《あの日の惨事を知るのは 僕と
スピードワゴンの ２人だけ｡➡
Speedwagon and I are the only ones who know the truth behind the tragedy, that day.
警察も 事故と
納得してくれたが…｡➡
The police have determined the fire to be an accident...
気になるのは 石仮面！➡
But that mask still troubles me.
I've searched this wreckage to no end...
がれきを掘っても 出てこない！➡
I can only hope it was shattered into pieces.
粉みじんになったと信じたい｡
そう思おう！➡
And that's all I can do... hope, and put it out of my mind.
そして 早く忘れよう》
Jojo!
≪(ｴﾘﾅ)ジョジョ｡
Erina!
エリナ…｡
ん？
Who was that?
《誰だ？
さっきから ずっといる…》
He's been following us for a while...
どうかしたの？
いや… 何でもな…｡
What's the matter?
Oh... It's noth--
ううっ!?
Jonathan Joestar, I presume?
(ﾂｪﾍﾟﾘ)
ジョナサン･ジョースター君…｡
そして そのレディーは
ミス エリナ･ペンドルトン｡
And the lady is Miss Erina Pendleton, correct?
Wh-Who are you?!
なっ!? 何者!?
I'm impressed... you managed to survive the power of that stone mask!
よく生き残れたものだ｡
あの 石仮面の力から！
パウ｡
うげぇ‼
ジョジョ！
Jojo!
くうっ… うふっ！
そうそう｡ 肺の中の空気を
１cc残らず 搾り出せ！
That's it, let every last cubic centimeter of air be expelled from your lungs...
(ｴﾘﾅ)ジョジョ～！
ケガしてる人に なんてことを！
Jojo!
What kind of monster attacks a wounded man?!
しばらく 呼吸はできん…
が 心配はいらん…｡
He'll be out of breath for just a moment.
But don't fret.
ぐはっ！ な… 何だ？
W-What the?!
W-What's happening... to my body... to my arm?!
な… 何だ!?
僕の体が！ う… 腕が！
I am Baron Zeppeli...
私は ツェペリ男爵だ｡
And courage alone will not be enough to defeat those of the stone mask...
勇気だけでは
石仮面には 勝てんよ｡
The pain from my broken arm...
複雑骨折した腕が！
ほとんど 痛みもない…｡
It's almost completely gone!
こんな重い石も 持てる！
信じられないわ！
I can lift this heavy stone easily!
How is that possible?!
W-What in the world did you do...?
い… 一体 何をした!?
君は… 何者だ!?
And who the hell are you?!
質問は １つずつにしてくれんかね
ジョジョ｡
One question at a time please, Jojo.
And it was not by my hand, it was your own breathing that eased the pain.
私が したのではない｡
君の呼吸が 痛みを消したのだよ｡
あっ！
ハ… ハプショッ！ れっ！
Ah... Achoo!
Why did you do this for me?!
なぜ 僕に こんなことを!?
どうして 僕の名を!?
あっ い… いない！
How do you know my name?!
H-He's gone...
質問は １つずつだってばさぁ
ジョジョ｡
I said one question at a time, Jojo.
It's far easier to show you what I mean. Come along.
答えを 見せてあげるよ｡
付いておいで｡
そして それを見て 私を知ったら
君の運命は また変わる！
Once you see the way and come to trust me... your fate will be forever changed!
私は 君の横隔膜を 指で突き
そして 特別な呼吸法にしたのだ｡
When I drove my finger into your diaphragm, it activated a special breathing technique.
特別な呼吸法？
A breathing technique?
呼吸が起こすエネルギーを
見せてあげよう｡
Let me show you the energy you
can wield with the right breathing...
W-What on earth is he doing?
な… 何をする気だろう？
スーハー スーハー｡
クゥゥゥォォォ！
コォォォォォォ！
What is this?!
あれは 一体？
な… 何だ？ あの波紋は!?
W-What are those Ripples?!
The way they're moving is totally unnatural!
あんな形 不自然だ！
What you are about to witness is the very same energy that soothed your agony!
今から見せるのは 君の痛みを
消したエネルギーと 同じもの！
るォォォォォ！
No, stop!
きゃあああ！
やめろ～！
はぁ～っ！
(カエルの鳴き声)
Th-The frog wasn't even hurt!
カ… カエルは 何ともない！
It is a meditative martial art.
これが 仙道だ！
せ… 仙道!?
M-Meditative martial art?
波紋エネルギーこそ 仙道パワー！
The energy of the Ripple that you saw is the power that fuels this martial art.
私の 波紋エネルギーは
カエルの肉体を➡
My Ripple flowed harmlessly through the frog's body before impacting the stone and splitting it.
波紋となって伝わり
岩を砕いたのだ！
ジョジョ… 私は知っている｡
Jojo! I know that the stone mask remains intact!
あの石仮面は 壊れていない｡
The man who used the mask, Dio, still has it!
石仮面の男
ディオが 持っている！
What?!
何だって!?
今 ディオと言ったのか!?
Did you say... Dio?!
Precisely!
そうだ！ そして 私は 何十年も
あの石仮面を 捜している｡
I have been searching for that stone mask for decades...
石仮面を 破壊するために！
...so that I may destroy it...
石仮面をかぶった者を
倒すために！
...and destroy all those who have been tainted by it!
It is your destiny to battle those of the stone mask!
君は 既に
石仮面と戦う運命にある！
You will master these techniques! Failure means certain death!
仙道を学ばなければならん！
さもないと 死ぬ！➡
For you, and the entire human race!
君も この全人類も！
T-This can't be real...
ま… まさか｡
Jojo, what is he talking about... what does this mean?!
ジョジョ 何のこと？
あの人は 一体…｡
E-Erina...
《エ… エリナ！➡
I... I can't let Erina get involved in this.
くっ… この件に
エリナを巻き込んではいけない｡➡
彼女だけは 決して！》
Not her... no matter what.
こ… これは!? は… 花が!?
A-Are those... are those flowers?!
《し… 信じられん！➡
I-Incredible!
腕の骨折を治した 波紋ｴﾈﾙｷﾞｰが
まだ 残っており➡
The Ripple energy that healed his arm is still coursing within him, and it's making those flowers bloom!
枯れかけた花が
再生されたんだ！➡
この ジョジョという青年は
とてつもない才能と力を➡
This young man named Jojo...
There is incredible potential and skill lying dormant within him...
眠らせているのかもしれん｡➡
This young man could be the savior of mankind!
この青年なら
世界を救えるかもしれんぞ！》
(女性)いやぁあ～！
No!!
んん～…｡
Little by little, my power is returning...
しだいしだいに
力が よみがえってきた｡
This is what they call the food chain.
食物連鎖というのがあったな｡
草は 豚に食われ
豚は 人間に食われる｡
Hogs feed on vegetation, and humans feed on the meat from those hogs...
我々は その人間を
糧としてるわけか｡
And we are the ones who consume those humans.
人間を食料としてこそ 真の帝王！
We feed on mankind, and this makes us
the true rulers of the world!
Jack! Do what you will with her...
ジャック 食っていいぞ｡
(ｼﾞｬｯｸ)ウシャー！
First I will bend the most wicked and impressionable people to my will...
まず 扱いやすい
邪悪な人間だけを しもべとし➡
一気に 世界を！
この世を 手中に収めてやる！
And then, the world!
All will be mine for the taking...
I will stand above the human race!
全ての人間の
頂点に立ってやる！
- 1 Week Later -
I have begun training in the secret of the Ripple from the man known as Zeppeli,
〈僕は ツェペリという
底知れぬ人物に➡
波紋エネルギーというものを習い
共に ディオと戦う決意をした｡➡
in preparation of our battle against Dio.
その理由は…〉
The reason he's helping me is...
ジョジョ｡ 私が仮面を追っている
理由を話そう｡
Jojo, let me tell you why I am pursuing that stone mask.
このツェペリ…
ウィル･Ａ･ツェペリは若かった｡
It was when I, Will A. Zeppeli, was about your age.
私は 未知の探求に
限りない興味を持つ 若者だった｡
In my youth, I had an endless fascination with the bizarre.
My father was a scholar and an archaeologist. I joined his research team, and I traveled the world.
学者であった父の
遺跡発掘隊に 参加した私は➡
世界中を旅して回った｡
そして アステカ遺跡へ
発掘に行ったときのこと｡
We were excavating an Aztec ruin...
まさか!?
そう｡ 事もあろうか➡
But that means...
Indeed! And as fate would have it, I was the first person to get their hands on the stone mask!
あの石仮面は
私が 偶然 発掘した物なのだよ｡
その帰国途中で 隊の中の１人が
何かのきっかけで 仮面をかぶり➡
It was on our voyage home when one of the excavation team somehow ended up activating the mask...
発現させた！
(ﾂｪﾍﾟﾘ)《うわ～！》
In his blood lust, he severed the heads of his former friends...
血に飢えた そいつは
友人の首を バックリ断ち切り➡
腕を 足を 体を
引きちぎりまくった！
He tore their bodies; one by one, limb from limb.
There was 58 men on that ship... none of them survived.
船員58名 皆殺しだった！
I dove into the ocean, but still, he followed me!
私は 海に飛び込んだが
そいつは 追ってきた！
(男性)《URRRRYYYY！》
《ゲブゥ！》
Wrrryyyy...
That was when the sun began to rise!
そのとき 夜が明けた！
In the light of dawn, I was able to see him clearly for the first time... his face...
朝日の光で 初めて見えた
そいつの顔は…｡
It was the face of the man who led our expedition... my father.
発掘隊の隊長 私の父だった｡
The stone mask drifted out to sea,
along with the ship that carried it...
石仮面を積んだままの船は
どこかへ 流されていった｡
I feared that someone else could discover the power of that stone mask one day...
私は 恐れた｡
いつか どこかで 石仮面の力が➡
再び 発現するだろうと！
そのための対抗手段を
考えておかねばなるまいと！
I decided that I needed to find some way to counteract it.
That's when I discovered the power of the Ripple.
そして
波紋法にたどりついたのだ！
The power of the Ripple is born from the flow of one's own blood.
波紋エネルギーは 自分の
血液の流れから 生み出すもの！
対して石仮面は 他人の血液から
エネルギーを吸い取る！
In contrast, the stone mask draws its power from the flowing blood of others.
形は 表と裏｡
同じエネルギーだったのだ！
They are opposing forces from the same source; two sides of the same coin!
Now I see!
そうか！ 波紋を消すには
もう１つの波紋を！
The only way to cancel out a Ripple is with an opposing one!
Precisely! When faced with a greater source of Ripple energy, they dissipate into nothing!
そうだ！ もう１つの 大きな
波紋エネルギーをぶつければ➡
やつらは 砕け散る！
そして 波紋法の作る
エネルギーの波は➡
Because the waves that radiate through the power of the Ripple...
...are on the same wavelength as the light of the sun itself!
太陽の光の波と 同じ形なのだ！
Mr. Zeppeli, please teach me to wield the power of the Ripple!
ツェペリさん 教えてください｡
波紋の使い方を！
どんな試練も 克服します｡
I'll endure whatever training you have in mind for me!
That's a relief, seeing as I would have used force if you refused!
嫌だと言っても
無理やり教えるわ！
世界の帝王になるために ディオは
まず ジョジョ 君を狙うはずだ｡
Because I believe that Dio sees you as the first obstacle in his quest to conquer the world, Jojo!
ウホホホッホッホーッ｡
Listen carefully, Jojo.
いいか ジョジョ
呼吸には 血液が関わっている｡
Your breathing is integral to your blood flow.
Your bloodstream carries oxygen from your lungs, after all.
血液は 酸素を 肺から運ぶからだ｡
そして 血液中の酸素は
体細胞に関わっている｡
And the oxygen brought by the flow of blood fuels your cells.
And those cells make up your body!
体細胞 イコール 肉体｡
つまり 水に波紋を起こすように
呼吸法によって➡
In other words, the same way a Ripple moves through water, your breathing can generate a Ripple from within your body.
肉体に波紋を起こし
エネルギーを作り出す！
Creating a potent source of energy!
あぶっ‼
He stretched his arm so his punch could reach me...
《手元で 急に グーンと伸びた！
どうなっているのだ!?》
How is that possible?!
I call it "Zoom Punch!"
名付けて ズームパンチ！
関節を外し 腕を伸ばす！
By dislocating my joints, I can extend the reach of my punch.
The power of the Ripple will minimize the pain done to your body.
その際の激痛は
波紋エネルギーで 和らげるのだ！
Jojo! Do not let this disrupt the rhythm of your breathing!
ジョジョ！
呼吸法のリズムを 狂わすなよ｡
波紋エネルギーは 精神の乱れに
すごく 敏感なのだよ｡
The power of the Ripple is extremely sensitive to your state of mind.
はい！
≪(ｽﾋﾟｰﾄﾞﾜｺﾞﾝ)お～い ｼﾞｮｰｽﾀｰさん！
Right!
Hey!
Mr. Joestar!
Speedwagon?
スピードワゴン！
A mountain village called Wind Knights Lot?
山あいの町
ウインドナイツ･ロット!?
Yeah, I confirmed that someone matching Dio's description was spotted there.
ええ｡ ディオらしいやつを➡
その町で見たって情報を
確認しました！
そこじゃ 最近
行方不明者が増えてるようです｡
And some of the townspeople have gone missing!
We're out of time. Jojo, you will have to perfect your Ripple breathing technique in combat.
時間がない｡ ジョジョ｡
波紋呼吸法の仕上げは
実戦でやるぞ！
Yes, sir! I'm ready to fight!
はい！
戦いの覚悟はできています！
You can count me in!
俺もだぜ！
This is the entrance to Wind Knights Lot!
(ｽﾋﾟｰﾄﾞﾜｺﾞﾝ)
お～ ウインドナイツ･ロットへの
入り口だ！
うん｡ 予定どおり
太陽のあるうちに 行動が取れる｡
We should still have some daylight left, just like we planned.
Erina, I left without saying goodbye...
《エリナに 何の挨拶もなしに
出てきてしまったな…》
でも 必ず帰る！
But I will return to you!
≪(物音)
あっ！
おっ？
どうしたんだ？
御者！ なぜ止めた!?
What's wrong?!
Coachman, why did you stop?
Be careful, sunlight doesn't reach this far into the tunnel!
気を付けろ！
ここは 太陽が届いていない！
Hey, coachman...
おい 御者！
うっ!? うわぁぁぁぁ～っ！
ディオか？ でも どこにいる!?
Was it Dio?
But where could he be?
Both of you... get away from the horses!
２人とも 馬から離れていなさい｡
(ｽﾋﾟｰﾄﾞﾜｺﾞﾝ)な… 何だ!? こいつは！
馬の体に 潜り込んでいる！
What the hell is this?! He crawled inside of the horse's body!
Mr. Joestar, this guy... this guy is bad news!
(ｽﾋﾟｰﾄﾞﾜｺﾞﾝ)ジョースターさん！
こいつは！ こいつはヤバい！
He's even more twisted and insane than Dio himself!
残虐性 異常性において
ディオ以上だ！
Dio already has minions like this to do his bidding?!
ディオは 既に
このような仲間を増やしている！
ふぅ…｡
２人とも 下がっていなさい｡
Both of you, step aside... I shall handle this.
私が戦う！
ゾンビだな｡
He's a zombie...
A creature granted power and eternal life, as long as it consumes human flesh.
人間を食って
永遠の生命と 力を与えられ➡
しかし ディオの思いのままに
操られる｡ いわば 肉人形…｡
But he is completely under Dio's control.
A simple puppet of flesh and blood.
I'm going to strike real terror within you... watch you turn pale...
最高の恐怖を与えて➡
青ざめた面にしてから
お前らの 鮮血の温かさを➡
And then I'll have myself a taste...
...of your warm blood!
味わってやるぜ！
Prepare to be killed like the insects you are!
絶望に 身をよじれ 虫けらども！
さて やつは どう出る？
わしが やつなら…｡
Now then, if I were him... how would I proceed?
This is an important lesson in combat psychology, Jojo.
ジョジョ これは
大事な物の考え方じゃぞ！
その１！ ｢もし 自分が敵なら｣と
相手の立場に 身を置く思考！
First, put yourself in your enemy's shoes, try to imagine what they must be thinking...
わしが やつなら！
まず 太陽までの逃げ道！
If I were him, I'd try to cut off our only path towards sunlight...
トンネルの入り口を塞ぐ！
I would collapse the entrance to the tunnel!
(ｼﾞｬｯｸ)えいや～っ！ いや～っ！
(ｽﾋﾟｰﾄﾞﾜｺﾞﾝ･ｼﾞｮﾅｻﾝ)ああっ！
(ｽﾋﾟｰﾄﾞﾜｺﾞﾝ)うわぁああ～っ！
馬車を ぶん投げて➡
He threw the carriage to make the tunnel collapse!
トンネルを 崩す気か！
飛べ！ スピードワゴン！
Run, Speedwagon!
来るぞ！
Here he comes!
ぬおおおお！
S-Switchblades are coming out of his body?!
ぜ… 全身から メスが！
That must be how he was able to skewer the horses and the coachman so quickly!
あ… あれか!? 一瞬のうちに
御者を串刺しにしたのは！
いやっ！
Ripple Cutter!
波紋カッター！
It appears that my Ripple Cutter is a bit shaper than your knives, old bean.
波紋カッターの方が
あんさんのメスより➡
よう 切れるわい｡
ジョジョ！
戦いの思考 その２じゃ！
Jojo, here's your next lesson on the psychology of battle.
ノミっているよなあ｡
ちっぽけな 虫けらのノミじゃよ！
Consider the flea. Those tiny little pests...
They will attack a human that towers over them without a moment's hesitation.
あの虫は 我々 巨大な人間に➡
所構わず
戦いを挑んでくるなあ！
これを 勇気と
呼べるだろうかね｡
But would you call that courage?
I certainly wouldn't say a flea is brave!
ノミどものは
勇気とは呼べんなあ｡
Then what exactly is courage?!
では 勇気とは 一体 何か!?
True courage comes from knowing fear itself! From conquering your fear!
勇気とは 怖さを知ること！
恐怖を
我が物とすることじゃあ！
It is fear that disrupts your breathing!
呼吸を乱すのは 恐怖！
だが 恐怖を支配したとき➡
But upon knowing your fear and conquering it, your breath will remain steady no matter what!
呼吸は 規則正しく 乱れない！
波紋法の呼吸は 勇気の産物！
The Ripple breathing technique is born from courage!
人間賛歌は 勇気の賛歌！
The achievements of man are the product of courage!
人間の素晴らしさは
勇気の素晴らしさ！
The magnificence of man is the splendor of courage!
However strong they may be, these zombies know nothing of courage!
いくら強くても
こいつらゾンビは 勇気を知らん！
They are nothing more than fleas!
ノミと 同類よ！
Meditative Wave Kick!
仙道ウェーブキーック！
おお！
The power of the Ripple destroys these beasts at a cellular level.
波紋エネルギーが 怪物の組織を
ズタズタに破壊したのだ！
Amazing! He didn't even spill his wine!
すげえ！
ワインを こぼしてもいねえ！
Jojo, I want you to finish him off.
ジョジョ 後は お前が仕上げしろ｡
やつの脳全体を溶かすのだ｡
You have to make sure the brain is destroyed... That's the only way to truly defeat a vampire!
吸血鬼を倒すには
それしかな～い！
うがあああッ！
よくも てめえら！
必ず ぶっ殺す！
You bastards! I'll kill every last one of you!
I'll shred you to pieces and devour you!
(ｼﾞｬｯｸ)
こま切れにして 食らってやるぜ！
まさか やつを追っていくんじゃ
ねえでしょうね！
Don't tell me... We're not going after him, are we?!
We have no choice...
行かにゃなるまい｡
But Jojo will be the only one going.
しかし 行くのは ジョジョ１人｡
ジョジョ！
Jojo!
Eliminate him without spilling a single drop of this wine.
そのワインを グラスから１滴も
こぼさずに やつを倒してこい！
ジョジョ
戦いの思考 その３じゃ！
Jojo... your third lesson in combat psychology...
There's an old saying from Norway...
北国ノルウェーに
こんな ことわざがある｡
"The northern winds are what made the Vikings."
｢北風が
勇者バイキングをつくった｣｡
そのワインを
１滴たりとも こぼしてみろ｡
Spill even the tiniest drop of that wine...
And I will abandon you, even if you manage to defeat him.
そのときは たとえ
やつを倒したとしても➡
わしは お前を もう見捨てる！
Hey!
(ｽﾋﾟｰﾄﾞﾜｺﾞﾝ)おい！ おっさんよ！
正気か てめえ！
Listen to yourself, gramps! Have you lost your bloody mind?!
Watch your tone!
あんたは だ～っとれい！
分かりました｡
I understand!
"The northern winds are what made the Vikings," right?
｢北風が バイキングをつくった｣
ですね？
うむ｡
《まるで 迷路だ｡
明かりで 照らしても➡
It's like a maze down here...
Even with the torch, there are plenty of areas covered in shadow...
必ず 闇の部分ができる構造に
造られている》
《ま… まずい｡ この火は！》
O-Oh no! This fire will mean--
うっ！
くっ！
うわぁぁぁ！
(ｼﾞｬｯｸ)んばばぁ！
I'm a walking target with this flame, I have to get rid of it!
《明かりを消さなければ
狙われるだけだ！➡
しかし もう
やつが どこから来るか➡
But now I have no way of knowing
where he could be attacking from...
こっちにも 分からない！》
I can smell you... I can smell the aroma of your blood...
(ｼﾞｬｯｸ)《臭うぜ！
あったけえ 血の臭いだ》
Combat psychology lesson one...
Put yourself in your enemy's shoes.
《戦いの思考 その１
｢敵の立場で考えよ！｣➡
He's close by.
やつは 近いはず！
そして 思考その２➡
Lesson two... Conquer your fear.
｢恐怖を我が物としろ！
そのとき 呼吸は 乱れない！｣》
That way my breathing won't be disrupted...
《来い！ けい動脈にかみついて
ビーンとかんだまま➡
A little closer... I'll bite into your neck and tear your arteries open!
血管を引っ張ってやる！》
The harsh northern winds are said to have made the Vikings hearty and clever in order to survive.
北極海の厳しい北風は➡
気骨ある
したたかなバイキングを生んだ｡
Simply put, overcoming hardship is an opportunity for growth.
すなわち 厳しい条件は➡
知恵しだいで チャンスにも
なりうるということだ｡
あのワインは
バイキングを つくるかな？
Do you think that wine test will make him into a Viking?
Because if it doesn't, he will never be able to defeat Dio.
でなければ
しょせん ディオには勝てん！
Th-This is the Ripple!
こ… これは 波紋!?
That's it... The wine is like the northern winds!
そうか 北風は このワインだ！
ワインの波紋を感じる！
グラスを伝わり➡
I can feel the Ripple coming from the wine!
Through the glass, through my arm, down my body, into the ground...
腕を伝わり 体を伝わり
地面を伝わり！
やつの生命の 振動を感じる！
このワインは 波紋探知機だ！
I can feel the pulse of his life!
This wine is a way for me to detect Ripples!
My heart is burning...
震えるぞ ハート！
燃え尽きるほど ヒート！
With the heat of a raging fire!
I have you now, you bloodsucking zombie!
そこだ 吸血ゾンビ！
壁を伝われ 波紋！
I'll send my Ripple through the wall...
仙道波紋オーバードライブ！
Meditative Art of the Ripple...
Overdrive!
Come on, give me that sweet blood already!
(ｼﾞｬｯｸ)《早く来い！
ベロベロ吸ってやるぜ！》
(ｼﾞｬｯｸ)
ホゲーッ！ くるゃああ～っ‼
I see you've realized my intentions with the wine, Jojo...
ワインの意味を 理解したらしいな
ジョジョ！
The harsh wind of struggle has given birth to a Viking!
よ～し
北風は バイキングをつくったぞ！
♬(ｴﾝﾃﾞｨﾝｸﾞﾃｰﾏ)
I'll be the roundabout
♬ I'll be the roundabout
The words will make you out 'n' out
♬ The words
will make you out'n'out
I'll spend the day your way
♬ I spend the day away
Call it morning driving through the sound and
♬ Call it morning
driving through
♬ the sound and
in and out the valley
In and out the valley
♬～
The music dance and sing
♬ The music dance and sing
They make the children really ring
♬ They make
the children really ring
I'll spend the day your way
♬ Spend the day away
Call it morning driving through the sound and
♬ Call it morning
driving through
♬ the sound and
in and out the valley
In and out the valley
In and around the lake
♬ In and around the lake
Mountains come out of the sky
♬ Mountains come out of
the sky and they stand there
and they stand there
One mile over we'll be there and we'll see you
♬ One mile over we'll be there
and we'll see you
♬ Ten true summers
Ten true summers we'll be there and laughing too
♬ we'll be there
and laughing too
Twenty-four before my love you'll see I'll be
♬ Twenty four before
my love you'll see
♬ I'll be there with you
There with you
Next Episode
At last, we meet!
What have you done, you bastard?!
Can he defeat these fearsome monsters?!
This is a duel of honor between heroes!
Dio, I'm putting an end to your twisted schemes!
Episode 5:
"The Black Knights"
とうとう会えたな｡
(ﾀﾙｶｽ･ﾌﾞﾗﾌｫｰﾄﾞ)呪いぬいてやる～‼
(ｽﾋﾟｰﾄﾞﾜｺﾞﾝ)勝てるのか!?
この すさまじい妄執に！
(ﾌﾞﾗﾌｫｰﾄﾞ)
これは 勇者としての決闘だ！
ディオ！
君の野望 僕が打ち砕く！